In a far corner of the Earth
在地球的另一个角落
is a South American wilderness.
是南美洲的荒野.
These extreme landscapes are home to strange and wonderful animals.
这些极端的景观是奇怪而奇妙的动物的家园.
From the rugged peaks of the Andes
从安第斯山脉崎岖的山峰
across the scorched desert steppe
穿过炙热的沙漠草原
to coasts battered by some of the roughest seas on the planet.
去遭受地球上最汹涌的海洋袭击的海岸.
Living here takes guts and determination.
住在这里需要勇气和决心.
There are incredible opportunities for some.
对某些人来说,有着难以置信的机会.
For others, it's a battle to survive.
对其他人来说,这是一场生存之战.
The pioneering spirit
开拓精神
unites them all
把他们团结起来
under the spell of Patagonia.
在巴塔哥尼亚的魔咒下.
Patagonia is an uncompromising wilderness.
巴塔哥尼亚是一片毫不妥协的荒野.
It is the name given to the tail end of South America,
它是南美洲尾部的名字,
straddling Chile and Argentina.
横跨智利和阿根廷.
Nowhere else on Earth is further south,
地球上没有其他地方在更南边,
except Antarctica,
除了南极洲,
and it is dominated by the Andes mountains,
它的主体是安第斯山脉,
which form a backbone over 1,000 miles long.
形成一个超过1000英里长的主干.
Following these towering peaks, we'll travel from north to south
沿着这些高耸的山峰,我们将从北向南旅行
where a clash between the elemental forces of fire
火元素之间的冲突
and ice
还有冰
create dramatically different worlds,
创造截然不同的世界,
shaping the fate of all Patagonians.
决定所有巴塔哥尼亚人的命运.
A lone call is caught on the wind.
一个孤独的电话被风吹走了.
A female puma.
一只雌性美洲狮.
Like all settlers here, she must be resilient and adaptable.
像这里所有的定居者一样,她必须有韧性和适应能力.
She's done well so far.
到目前为止她做得很好.
Precious cubs, just six weeks old.
珍贵的幼崽,只有六周大.
All three still covered in spots.
三个地方都还布满了斑点.
It will take Mum over a year to pass on all her skills.
妈妈要花一年多的时间才能把所有的技能传授给别人.
In Patagonia, the tiniest details mark the difference
在巴塔哥尼亚,最微小的细节标志着差异
between success and failure.
在成功和失败之间.
This secret den is their sanctuary.
这个秘密的巢穴是他们的避难所.
Protected from wild weather and wandering predators.
免受恶劣天气和四处游荡的食肉动物的侵袭.
For now, it's all about play.
现在,一切都是为了玩.
The first step on a long road to become hunters.
成为猎人漫长道路上的第一步.
But in Patagonia, you can't hide away forever.
但在巴塔哥尼亚,你不能永远躲着.
Mum must lead her cubs to face the wilderness head on.
妈妈必须带领她的幼崽正面面对荒野.
In this elemental land, the very foundations are constantly shifting.
在这片原始的土地上,根基在不断地变化.
Fire is reshaping and building the Andes.
火正在重塑和建造安第斯山脉.
Eruptions spew out jets of ash at over 200mph
火山喷发以每小时200英里的速度喷出火山灰
blasting immense plumes ten miles high.
喷射出十英里高的巨大羽状物.
Debris explodes from the crater with the power of an atomic bomb
碎片以原子弹的威力从火山口爆炸
every ten seconds.
每十秒钟.
The volcano's ash cloud becomes super-charged,
火山灰云变得超级带电,
sparking dramatic bolts of lightning.
引发戏剧性的闪电.
In northern Patagonia, volcanoes are very much alive.
在巴塔哥尼亚北部,火山非常活跃.
Dawn reveals an alien world.
黎明揭示了一个陌生的世界.
It looks primeval, yet this landscape is only a few years old.
它看起来很原始,但这片风景只有几年的历史.
This is a mountain still in the making.
这是一座正在形成的山.
It looks like a snowscape, but in fact,
看起来像雪景,但事实上,
it is ash over five metres deep,
它是五米深的火山灰,
layered with lava and gases.
由熔岩和气体分层.
These may look like stunted trees,
这些看起来像矮树,
but they are just the tips of a forest, buried alive.
但它们只是森林的顶端,被活埋了.
Yet Patagonia is full of surprises.
然而巴塔哥尼亚充满了惊喜.
Remarkable trees, from the time of dinosaurs.
从恐龙时代开始的非凡树木.
Their leaves, like spiky scales, grow in spirals.
它们的叶子像尖尖的鳞片,呈螺旋状生长.
From the lava grow islands of monkey puzzles.
从熔岩中生长出猴子拼图岛.
They survive the intense heat radiating from the black lava,
它们在黑色熔岩散发出的强烈热量中幸存下来,
absorbing minerals from the parched ground.
从干燥的地面上吸收矿物质.
Their bark is fire-resistant,
它们的树皮是耐火的,
and holding their branches high once kept them out of reach
曾经高高举起树枝让它们够不着
of hungry dinosaurs.
饥饿的恐龙.
But now, these monkey puzzles are home to some of their descendants.
但现在,这些猴子拼图是他们的一些后代的家.
Austral parakeets.
南方长尾鹦鹉.
The most southerly parrot species in the world.
世界上最南端的鹦鹉种类.
They come for the huge cones.
他们来取巨大的圆锥体.
Weighing in at nearly 1kg,
体重接近1公斤,
each is a feast over 200 seeds.
每场盛宴有200多粒种子.
It's a bonanza in this scorched land.
在这片焦土上是一笔财富.
But the monkey puzzles all produce their cones at once,
但是猴子的谜题都是一次产生锥状体,
so even a flock of parakeets cannot eat them all,
所以即使是一群长尾鹦鹉也不能吃掉它们,
allowing these ancient trees to be Patagonia's enduring survivors.
让这些古树成为巴塔哥尼亚不朽的幸存者.
This volcanic world is the northern gateway of the Patagonian Andes.
这个火山世界是巴塔哥尼亚安第斯山脉的北部门户.
A mountainous backbone,
多山的脊梁,
up to 4,000m high,
高达4000米,
almost 100 miles wide.
差不多100英里宽.
The Andes are the weather-makers, trapping the moisture driving in
安第斯山脉是天气的制造者,它将湿气聚集起来
from the Pacific Ocean.
来自太平洋.
As they stretch south, they create increasingly remote worlds,
当他们向南延伸时,他们创造了越来越遥远的世界,
with curious creatures.
和奇怪的生物在一起.
But the Andes sow the seeds of their own destruction
但是安第斯山脉播下了自己毁灭的种子
in the moisture they trap.
在潮湿的环境中它们会被困住.
Millions of snow flakes build glaciers
数以百万计的雪花形成了冰川
which cling to the highest pinnacles.
依附在最高的山峰上.
And each summer meltwater unleashes its raw power.
每年夏天融水都会释放出它的原始能量.
It begins with a drip.
从点滴开始.
A trickle melts its way into the glacier's icy heart.
一条细流融进冰河冰冷的心脏.
It gathers pace and volume.
它聚集了速度和音量.
Racing to the edge of these hanging glaciers.
奔向这些悬而未决的冰川边缘.
This water generates immense power as it falls
这些水下落时产生巨大的能量
pummelling the base rock below,
击打下面的基岩,
drilling back into the cliff.
钻回悬崖.
These great thundering cascades sculpt a new world.
这些巨大的雷鸣般的瀑布塑造了一个新世界.
To the west side of the Andes is a narrow green band of life
安第斯山脉西侧是一条狭窄的绿色生命带
hemmed in between the peaks and the coast,
环绕在山峰和海岸之间,
shaped not by fire but by water.
不是由火而是由水塑造的.
Countless rivers carve their path through the rock,
无数的河流在岩石中划出一条路,
whipping up some of the best white water on the planet.
制造出地球上最好的白水.
For Diego Valsecchi and his team,
对于迭戈·瓦尔塞奇和他的团队,
this elemental challenge is irresistible.
这种基本的挑战是不可抗拒的.
Dropping over 3,000m, the descents are rapid.
下降超过3000米,下降很快.
Round here they have names for torrents like these -
在这里他们有这样的洪流的名字-
la Garganta del Diablo.
暗黑破坏神.
The devil's throat.
魔鬼的喉咙.
Only the most skilful paddlers would risk a double waterfall.
只有最熟练的桨手才会冒着双瀑布的危险.
Two drops and the turmoil between them.
两滴和他们之间的混乱.
The approach is everything.
方法就是一切.
Diego is safely through,
迭戈安全通过了,
but for one creature, mastering the rapids is not a choice
但是对于一个生物来说,掌握急流不是一个选择
but a necessity.
但这是必要的.
Torrent ducks who forage for insects living in this white water.
在这片白水里觅食昆虫的急流鸭.
They're experts with the right tools.
他们是有合适工具的专家.
Big feet create explosive acceleration.
大脚带来爆发式加速.
Stiff tail feathers brace against the force of the water.
坚硬的尾羽顶住了水的力量.
And they can always fly out of danger.
它们总能飞出危险.
But their chicks have none of these advantages.
但是它们的小鸡没有这些优势.
They're just a few days old.
它们才几天大.
Yet Mum and Dad must teach them to master the rapids or they'll starve.
但是爸爸妈妈必须教他们如何驾驭急流,否则他们会饿死的.
Even in the shallows, these chicks look unsteady
即使在浅滩,这些小鸡看起来也不稳定
but there's a much greater challenge ahead.
但前面还有更大的挑战.
The aerated water of the falls creates prized feeding grounds.
瀑布的充气水创造了珍贵的觅食场所.
But the currents are fierce.
但是水流很湍急.
Weighing little over an ounce, these fluffballs must learn fast
这些毛绒球重一盎司多一点,学起来一定很快
or face being swept away.
或者脸被卷走.
Mum leads them down the side of the falls.
妈妈领着他们走下瀑布边.
Their goal is a rocky island.
他们的目标是一个岩石岛屿.
Mum and Dad gather their chicks.
妈妈和爸爸把他们的小鸡收集起来.
And they're off.
他们走了.
The ducklings' downy feathers trap air like a life-jacket
小鸭柔软的羽毛像救生衣一样锁住空气
as they bob across the surface.
当他们在水面上摇摆时.
It's a good start.
这是个好的开始.
But one chick is swept away.
但是一只小鸡被卷走了.
Mum and Dad look frantically for their missing duckling.
爸爸妈妈疯狂地寻找他们失踪的小鸭.
In the chaos, they have to make a difficult choice.
在混乱中,他们不得不做出艰难的选择.
Risk everything for a rescue, or keep their other chick safe?
冒着一切危险去营救,还是保护他们的另一只小鸡？
They push across the final current to the rock.
他们穿过最后的水流到达岩石.
Mum makes a break for it.
妈妈休息一下.
One lone chick struggles through.
一只孤独的小鸡挣扎着穿过.
Swiftly followed by Dad.
爸爸紧随其后.
The rock is a refuge, but the insects they eat
岩石是避难所,但它们吃的昆虫
live underwater, so this duckling has to go in again.
住在水下,所以这只小鸭必须再进去.
Luckily, the island gives shelter from the full force of the torrents.
幸运的是,这座岛能躲过汹涌的洪水.
Now its downy feathers make it too buoyant to dive.
现在它柔软的羽毛使它浮力太大而不能潜水.
So in the shallows, it grips the riverbed with its tiny feet
所以在浅水处,它用它的小脚抓住河床
and drives its head underwater.
把它的头埋在水里.
Today, these parents have led their duckling
今天,这些父母已经牵着他们的小鸭
through its toughest rite of passage.
通过最艰难的成人仪式.
But other creatures avoid these perils
但其他生物却避免了这些危险
and instead seek sanctuary in the rain-drenched forests
在被雨水淋湿的森林里寻找庇护所
that fringe the river banks.
在河岸边.
To the Chilean poet Pablo Neruda,
智利诗人聂鲁达,
this was a fragrant, silent, tangled jungle.
这是一片芬芳、寂静、纠结的丛林.
Trees are ancient, slow-growing giants.
树木是古老的,生长缓慢的巨人.
These rainforests may look lush,
这些雨林看起来很茂盛,
but they are surprisingly cold and challenging.
但他们出人意料的冷酷和富有挑战性.
The water brings life, but also washes away crucial nutrients.
水带来了生命,但也冲走了至关重要的营养.
So creatures here have ingenious solutions
所以这里的生物有巧妙的解决办法
to a life of thin pickings.
过着一种贫乏的生活.
Welcome to the Patagonian forest of miniatures.
欢迎来到巴塔哥尼亚微型画森林.
It's a tiny world.
这是一个很小的世界.
These pudu deer are only the size of a small dog.
这些普渡鹿只有小狗那么大.
And their newborn fawns would fit in the palm of your hand
它们新生的小鹿就可以放在你的手掌里
making their kind the smallest deer in the world,
使它们成为世界上最小的鹿,
because building a small body is a smart solution to limited resources.
因为建立一个小的身体是一个聪明的解决方案,有限的资源.
But others go further.
但其他人更进一步.
This minute Darwin's frog is just an inch tall.
这一分钟达尔文的青蛙只有一英寸高.
He's a strange dad, eating his own eggs six weeks ago.
他是个奇怪的爸爸,六周前还在吃自己的蛋.
They became tadpoles in a pouch in his throat,
它们变成了他喉咙里的蝌蚪,
where he secretes juices to feed them.
在那里他分泌汁液来喂养它们.
Now up to 20 froglets are wriggling to get out.
现在有多达20只青蛙在蠕动着想要逃出去.
These newborns have had a uniquely Patagonian start in life.
这些新生儿在生活中有着独特的巴塔哥尼亚式的开端.
This Patagonian mistletoe, or quintral, is a parasite.
这种巴塔哥尼亚槲寄生,或者叫昆特拉尔,是一种寄生虫.
Tendrils grow into its host tree to steal precious sugars.
卷须长到它的寄主树上偷取珍贵的糖分.
But how to spread and find new hosts?
但是如何传播和寻找新的宿主呢？
It begins with innocent-looking flowers laced with nectar.
它以花蜜点缀的纯真花朵开始.
The quintral bribes the only creature up to the job.
五分之一的人是唯一能胜任这项工作的人.
The green-backed firecrown hummingbird.
绿背火冠蜂鸟.
These firecrowns, weighing less than a ten pence piece,
这些火冠,不到10便士,
rely on this nectar to survive, so they fiercely defend territories
依靠这种花蜜生存,所以他们激烈地保卫领土
to protect their lifeline.
保护他们的生命线.
At 40 wing beats per second,
以每秒40次的速度,
this aerial combat is exhausting.
这场空战让人筋疲力尽.
So they must eat up to four times their body weight in nectar each day.
因此,它们每天必须吃四倍于体重的花蜜.
Then the quintral's pollen is brushed onto their feathers
然后五尾龙的花粉被刷到它们的羽毛上
and carried away to complete pollination.
然后被带走完成授粉.
At the end of each day,
每天结束时,
the hummingbird must go into torpor, a nightly hibernation,
蜂鸟必须进入迟钝状态,夜间冬眠,
slowing its metabolism by over 80%
新陈代谢减慢80%以上
while the quintral is only halfway through its mission.
而昆特拉尔号的任务只完成了一半.
For the next step, it lures in a curious nocturnal specialist.
下一步,它会吸引一位好奇的夜间专家.
Monito del monte - literally, "monkey of the mountain."
蒙尼托·德尔蒙特——字面意思是“山上的猴子”
The last of their kind, survivors of an ancient lineage,
他们中的最后一个,古老世系的幸存者,
not of monkeys, but of marsupials.
不是猴子,而是有袋动物.
This family of diminutive climbers are ancestors of the kangaroos,
这个小型登山者家族是袋鼠的祖先,
but in the trees they use their grasping tails
但在树上它们用它们的尾巴抓
while looking for their favourite food.
一边寻找他们最喜欢的食物.
Quintral berries.
五香浆果.
The fruits are bitter with a sticky seed.
这些水果有一颗黏糊糊的种子,很苦.
But for the quintral, every seed thrown away is as good as dead.
但对于五分之一的人来说,每一粒被扔掉的种子都像死了一样.
It needs to be swallowed.
需要吞下去.
Some seeds are harder to get rid of than others.
有些种子比其他种子更难除掉.
For the few seeds that do get eaten,
为数不多的种子会被吃掉,
success only comes when they have passed through a monito.
成功只有在他们经历了一段磨难之后才会到来.
The seed comes out much as it went in,
种子一进就出,
trailing gluey string to help catch any branch.
有助于抓住任何树枝的胶状细绳.
Finally deposited, the mistletoe has achieved its goal.
最后,槲寄生达到了它的目的.
Over the next two weeks, the seed will germinate
在接下来的两周里,种子将发芽
and bore into its new host to begin its parasitic life.
进入新的宿主开始寄生生活.
Hummingbirds, monitos and the quintral are an unlikely trio,
蜂鸟、莫尼托斯和金特拉尔是不太可能的三人组,
now dependent on each other to survive in this cold forest,
为了在这片寒冷的森林里生存,我们彼此依靠,
where otherwise they could not.
否则他们就不能.
Further south, the forests get colder,
再往南,森林会变冷,
until they meet an impenetrable wall of ice.
直到他们遇到一堵无法穿透的冰墙.
A perfect combination of high mountains and massive snowfall
高山和大雪的完美结合
have locked the Andes in a frozen grip stretching west from the peaks
把安第斯山脉锁定在从山峰向西延伸的冰冻地带
to the rugged coast.
去崎岖的海岸.
The temperature drops to 20 below zero.
温度降到零下20度.
It seems as if all life stops.
似乎所有的生命都停止了.
These are the largest southern ice sheets outside Antarctica,
这是南极洲以外最大的南部冰原,
covering over 6,500 square miles,
面积超过6500平方英里,
locking up over three trillion tonnes of water.
锁住了超过3万亿吨的水.
But astonishingly, beyond this wasteland, a new world is revealed
但令人惊讶的是,在这片荒地之外,一个新的世界出现了
where the ice has ground the Andes to their knees
冰把安第斯山脉夷为平地
and shaped a final frontier.
最终形成了一个边界.
The mountains are fragmented and scarred,
群山支离破碎,伤痕累累,
with only the granite towers of ancient magma standing tall.
只有古老岩浆的花岗岩塔屹立不倒.
The locals call this region Ultima Esperanza, or "Last Hope".
当地人称这个地区为“最后的希望”.
Yet the spirit of Patagonia is unbroken.
然而巴塔哥尼亚的精神是完整的.
This is a lost world of resilient and hardy souls.
这是一个失去了弹性和顽强的灵魂世界.
Secretive and agile, wild horses roam the most remote valleys
神秘而敏捷的野马在最偏远的山谷里游荡
and Patagonian cowboys, or gauchos,
巴塔哥尼亚牛仔,
ride out as a team to try and catch them.
作为一个团队去尝试抓住他们.
When these guys need a new horse,
当这些人需要一匹新马时,
an arisco, or wild horse, is the best you can get.
阿里斯科,或野马,是最好的你可以得到.
The ariscos are the descendants of escaped horses
阿里斯科人是逃跑的马的后代
brought by European settlers over the centuries.
几个世纪以来欧洲殖民者带来的.
It takes coordination to round them up.
把他们召集起来需要协调.
Vitito leads the drive to a remote corral.
维蒂托把车开到一个偏僻的畜栏.
With the horses, it's all about attitude.
对马来说,一切都取决于态度.
The gauchos have to catch
高乔人必须抓住
and get a bridle on each horse they want to break.
给每匹马套上缰绳.
Lassoing must be done at speed,
套索必须快速进行,
dropping the lasso just before the galloping front feet
在疾驰的前脚前放下套索
then snatching it tight as they step into the trap.
然后在他们跨入陷阱时紧紧抓住它.
But their raw strength tests the men.
但他们的原始力量考验着这些人.
A kick from a hoof could be fatal.
一个脚踢可能是致命的.
With the ariscos subdued,
阿里斯科被制服后,
the gauchos make the day long trek back to the main ranch,
高乔一家长途跋涉一天回到大牧场,
where taming can begin.
驯服开始的地方.
From the wild herd, they have chosen just three.
他们从野生动物群中只挑选了三只.
Today, the focus intensifies.
今天,焦点更加集中.
Vitito will face one arisco alone.
维蒂托将单独面对一个阿里斯科.
Each gaucho has his own style of taming.
每个高乔人都有自己的驯服风格.
The mare has to decide whether to trust Vitito.
母马必须决定是否信任维蒂托.
He watches her ears, her nostrils.
他看着她的耳朵,鼻孔.
Patiently, he works his magic.
他耐心地施魔法.
In just three hours, this mare has gone from wild to tame
仅仅三个小时,这匹母马就从野生变成驯养
as she begins a new life with the gauchos.
她和高乔一家开始了新的生活.
To survive this far south,
为了在这遥远的南方生存,
you need specialist skills,
你需要专业技能,
but they take time to learn.
但是他们需要时间去学习.
Wandering over these windswept, grassy plains
在这些狂风吹过的草地上徘徊
are big herds of guanacos,
是一大群瓜纳科斯鸟,
wild ancestors of the llama
美洲驼的野生祖先
and they are the favourite prey of Patagonia's biggest predator.
它们是巴塔哥尼亚最大的掠食者最喜欢的猎物.
Puma.
彪马.
Her snooze is interrupted by her boisterous sister.
她吵闹的姐姐打断了她的打盹.
These two teenagers are just beginning life
这两个青少年才刚刚开始生活
without Mum to provide for them.
没有妈妈照顾他们.
One is tailless, a defect since birth.
一个是无尾的,一个天生的缺陷.
Now 15 months old,
现在15个月大,
they will have to turn their games into successful hunts to survive.
他们将不得不把他们的游戏变成成功的狩猎来生存.
Late afternoon is the time when pumas begin to feel hungry.
傍晚是美洲狮开始感到饥饿的时候.
Such open country means they can easily see their prey
如此开阔的地方意味着它们很容易看到猎物
but in a land without trees there is nowhere to hide.
但在一片没有树木的土地上,没有地方可以藏身.
A lone guanaco.
孤零零的瓜纳科.
Tailless joins her sister
没有尾巴的加入了她姐姐的行列
but isn't welcome.
但不受欢迎.
By hunting together, there's twice the chance of being spotted.
一起打猎,被发现的几率是原来的两倍.
But she doesn't wait.
但她没有等.
She's blown their cover.
她揭穿了他们的伪装.
Ultimately, the sisters must become solitary hunters.
最终,姐妹俩必须成为孤独的猎人.
Perhaps it is time to go it alone.
也许是时候单独行动了.
But it won't be easy in this unpredictable world.
但在这个变幻莫测的世界里,这并不容易.
This far south, the weather is more treacherous.
在这遥远的南方,天气更加变幻莫测.
A snow flurry ramps into a blizzard in minutes.
一场暴风雪几分钟后就变成了暴风雪.
But with coarse outer hairs and warm under-fur,
但有粗糙的外毛和温暖的皮毛,
these guanacos cope with the cold.
这些瓜纳哥能御寒.
Andean condors,
安第斯秃鹰,
Patagonia's heaviest flying birds, must find a ledge while there is
巴塔哥尼亚最重的飞鸟,必须找到一个壁架,而有
still enough lift in the chilling air to raise their bulky bodies.
在寒冷的空气中还有足够的升力来举起它们庞大的身体.
As the weather clears,
随着天气转晴,
the storm has claimed a victim.
暴风雨夺走了一个受害者.
The guanaco carcass is quickly found by small falcons, chimangos,
瓜纳科的尸体很快就被小猎鹰发现了,
but their discovery won't go unnoticed for long.
但他们的发现不会被忽视太久.
This is young crested caracara has the advantage of being almost
这是年轻的凤头卡拉有优势,几乎是
twice the size of the chimangos,
两倍于芝麻果的大小,
and has come to stake his claim on this frozen buffet.
他来为这个冷冻自助餐打赌.
But with all his posturing, he's too slow.
但他装腔作势,动作太慢了.
Yellow-beaked adults are hard on his heels
黄喙的成年人紧跟其后
and he is pushed away before he can even get a bite.
他还没来得及咬一口就被推开了.
All he can do is watch
他所能做的就是看着
while the grown-ups make the most of their opportunity.
而成年人则充分利用了他们的机会.
Another contender approaches,
另一个竞争者靠近了,
as much a predator as a scavenger.
像食腐动物一样是捕食者.
It's time for a sharp exit.
是时候急着离开了.
A culpeo fox,
一只狐狸,
the largest of Patagonia's foxes.
巴塔哥尼亚最大的狐狸.
He's an opportunist with a voracious appetite.
他是一个贪得无厌的机会主义者.
Round here, they call him el zorro de los Andes.
在这里,人们叫他埃尔·佐罗·德·洛斯·安第斯.
He's not one to be rushed.
他不是一个急于求成的人.
Time to clean up after a welcome meal, with a little snow bathing.
吃过欢迎餐,洗个澡,该打扫卫生了.
Andean condors can spot a carcass from over a mile.
安第斯秃鹰能在一英里外发现一具尸体.
As the main clean-up squad flies in
当主要的清理小组飞来的时候
the young caracara is back
年轻的卡拉回来了
and this time it's a case of David and Goliath.
这次是大卫和歌利亚的案子.
He's faced with a wall of feathers three feet high.
他面对着一堵三英尺高的羽毛墙.
There seems to be no way through for the young caracara.
年轻的卡拉似乎没有出路.
A gang of condors can strip a carcass in a few hours.
一群秃鹰能在几个小时内剥下一具尸体.
He looks for a way in before there's nothing left.
他在一无所有之前想办法进去.
Condors can gorge themselves on over 2kg of meat.
秃鹰能吞下超过2公斤的肉.
The juvenile finally gets a chance.
少年终于有机会了.
Hardly a feast but it'll be just enough.
虽然不是什么盛宴,但也就足够了.
Growing up in Patagonia's far south,
在巴塔哥尼亚遥远的南方长大,
you have to keep your wits about you,
你得保持头脑清醒,
but more than anything, you can never give up.
但最重要的是,你不能放弃.
This youngster is now alone,
这个年轻人现在孤身一人,
a step closer to independence.
离独立又近了一步.
A herd of guanaco has many eyes on lookout.
一群瓜纳科鸟有许多眼睛在了望.
Even for one puma to get close takes great skill.
即使一只美洲狮靠得近也需要高超的技巧.
The lead male guanaco walks ahead.
领头的雄性瓜纳科走在前面.
The hunt is on.
狩猎开始了.
With only one ear, he is vulnerable.
只有一只耳朵,他很脆弱.
Perhaps a weakness the puma can exploit.
也许是美洲狮可以利用的弱点.
Pumas need to get within 20m for a fighting chance
美洲狮需要在20米以内才能有战斗的机会
and this hillside is practically bare.
而这个山坡几乎是光秃秃的.
The guanaco will bolt downhill
瓜纳科号将下山
so the puma hunts from below.
所以美洲狮从下面狩猎.
It freezes, exposed.
它冻结了,暴露了.
Yet its coat blends impressively into the landscape
然而,它的皮毛与风景融为一体,令人印象深刻
almost impossible to spot.
几乎不可能被发现.
In a long chase, the guanaco will always win,
在漫长的追逐中,瓜纳科队总会赢,
so the puma needs an element of surprise.
所以美洲狮需要一点惊喜.
Tense and focused,
紧张专注,
the ambush is set.
伏击开始了.
After 40 minutes stock still,
40分钟后,
the puma strikes.
美洲狮出击了.
Not fast enough.
速度不够快.
But the puma's got the whole night ahead.
但美洲狮还有一整晚的时间呢.
While a guanaco's eyesight weakens in the darkness,
当一只鸟的视力在黑暗中减弱时,
the puma's vision could give her the edge.
美洲狮的视力可以给她优势.
Under the Southern Cross,
在南十字之下,
the winds race and the temperature plummets.
狂风呼啸,气温骤降.
At dawn, the lakes are fringed with ice.
黎明时分,湖边结满了冰.
Condors are on the wing,
秃鹰在飞翔,
looking for fresh carcasses.
寻找新鲜的尸体.
Overnight, the sister has finally made a kill,
一夜之间,妹妹终于杀了人,
disguising it from prying eyes with scrub.
用刷子把它从窥探的眼睛里遮住.
She has come of age.
她已经成年了.
She can eat 7kg of meat at a sitting,
她一次能吃7公斤肉,
her teeth effortlessly slicing flesh from bone.
她的牙齿毫不费力地把肉从骨头上切下来.
Her kill will give her enough food for the next few days,
她的杀戮能让她在接下来的几天里有足够的食物,
but only if the condors don't find it first.
但前提是秃鹰没有先找到它.
Her tailless sister has not done so well.
她没有尾巴的妹妹做得不太好.
She looks small,
她看起来很小,
alone in this wide world
独自在这个广阔的世界里
as she heads back to familiar territory.
当她回到熟悉的领域.
After many days apart,
相隔多日,
the sisters are reunited.
姐妹们团聚了.
Their bond is proving hard to break.
他们的关系很难打破.
It may take up to five months
可能需要5个月的时间
for these siblings to permanently separate.
让这些兄弟姐妹永久分开.
They'll take a little longer to master their realm.
他们需要一点时间来掌握自己的领域.
Finally, at the tip of the Americas,
最后,在美洲的尖端,
Patagonia fragments into windswept islands.
巴塔哥尼亚岛被风吹得支离破碎.
Here, the Andes are swallowed by the ferocious Southern Ocean.
在这里,安第斯山脉被凶猛的南大洋吞没.
Yet along their length
但是沿着他们的长度
elemental forces have created contrasting worlds
元素的力量创造了截然不同的世界
sustaining a unique diversity of life.
维持生命的独特多样性.
Here, resourceful creatures learn the specialist skills
在这里,足智多谋的生物学习专业技能
they need to survive in their own domain
他们需要在自己的领域生存
so they can call Patagonia home.
所以他们可以打电话给巴塔哥尼亚.
Over a year, BBC film crews travelled the length of Patagonia
一年多来,英国广播公司的电影摄制组穿越了巴塔哥尼亚
to reveal little-known stories.
揭露鲜为人知的故事.
The most captivating encounter of all
最迷人的邂逅
was in the Patagonian Wild West,
在巴塔哥尼亚荒野的西部,
the world of the gauchos,
高乔人的世界,
Patagonia's cowboys.
巴塔哥尼亚牛仔队.
The remote estancia where they were headed was vast,
他们要去的遥远的地方很大,
40,000 hectares of rugged country,
40000公顷崎岖的乡村,
five hours from the nearest town.
离最近的城镇有五个小时的路程.
Epa, amigo!
环保署,朋友！
It's horses that make life possible here
是马使这里的生活成为可能
and these gauchos are the master horseman of South America.
这些高乔人是南美洲的骑士大师.
The team's challenge was to film them catching and breaking in wild horses.
这个团队的挑战是拍摄他们捕捉和驯服野马的过程.
Around a Patagonian barbecue,
在巴塔哥尼亚烧烤的周围,
the crew were welcomed with a special tradition.
船员们以特殊的传统受到欢迎.
I'm trying a bit of mate.
我在试着找个伴侣.
It's absolutely delicious.I really like it.
绝对好吃.我真的很喜欢.
Esta bueno, esta frio? What is it?
好,冷吗？ 它是什么？
No, no esta frio.Esta bueno, no? Si.Si, esta bueno.
不,不冷,很好,不是吗？ 是,很好.
So, it's a herb, or collection of herbs, that you put hot water on
所以,这是一种草药,或草药的集合,你放热水在上面
and then you suck it through a straw and you pass it round.
然后你用吸管吸吮它然后把它传过来.
Traditionally, it's a drink that everyone shares.
传统上,这是一种人人共享的饮料.
To find the elusive wild horses
寻找难以捉摸的野马
meant a day's trek further into the wilderness,
意味着一天的长途跋涉进入荒野,
and the only way to get there was to saddle up.
到那里的唯一方法就是备好马鞍.
So, we'd heard about these wild horses.
所以,我们听说过这些野马.
People told us that they were in the most remote valleys,
人们告诉我们他们在最偏远的山谷里,
that they were impossible to find,
他们不可能找到,
and that, even if you got a glimpse of them,
即使你看到了他们,
they would disappear over the horizon,
它们会消失在地平线上,
so we knew it was going to be really tricky.
所以我们知道这会很棘手.
The wild horses originally came from Europe.
野马最初来自欧洲.
The gauchos, too, came here from elsewhere.
高乔人也是从别处来的.
But they had fallen in love with this landscape and stayed.
但他们却爱上了这片风景,留下来了.
We'd ridden for hours, we'd set up, we were super quiet
我们骑了好几个小时,准备好了,非常安静
and waiting and then we finally caught a glimpse of the wild horses.
等待着,我们终于瞥见了野马.
The whole herd thundering towards us and the ground was shaking.
整个兽群向我们轰鸣而来,地面在颤抖.
The gauchos push the wild horses into the corral
高乔人把野马推进畜栏
and then the team had to find their star horse.
然后球队必须找到他们的明星马.
One stood out instantly.
其中一个瞬间脱颖而出.
A spirited black stallion.
一匹精力充沛的黑种马.
That black stallion was so proud,
那匹黑种马太骄傲了,
he had such a raw power,
他有如此原始的力量,
but it was really tense as Vitito tried to get a bridle on him.
但是,当他试图勒住缰绳时,真的很紧张.
The gauchos have great respect for these horses,
高乔人非常尊敬这些马,
but there's no place for sentimentality.
但没有多愁善感的地方.
Finally roped up, he was left to calm down.
最后用绳子把他捆起来,让他冷静下来.
That evening, Toby found out a little more about
那天晚上,托比发现了更多关于
how tough gaucho life can be.
高乔人的生活有多艰难.
How often do these guys get hurt?
这些人多久受伤一次？
Every once in a while.And when you get hit, you get hit hard.
每隔一段时间.当你被击中时,你会受到重击.
Really? Cos it's so remote, if things go wrong, it's serious.
真的？因为太遥远了,如果出了问题,那就严重了.
Yes, si.
是的,是的.
No-one left.
没有人离开.
There's nothing to eat in him,
他没什么吃的,
so they're joking.
所以他们在开玩笑.
Only bones! Only bones!
只有骨头！只有骨头！
The next morning, the crew went ahead to film the gauchos
第二天早上,摄制组继续拍摄高乔一家
bringing the wild horses back from the mountains
把野马从山上带回来
and very quickly, it was obvious something was wrong.
很快,很明显出了问题.
They came down the hill, we were all looking for the black stallion
他们下山来了,我们都在找那匹黑种马
and he wasn't there.
他不在那里.
And that was our key star character gone.
那是我们的关键明星角色消失了.
Alberto explained to us what had happened.
阿尔贝托向我们解释了发生的事情.
He was tied up and this got cut off and the horse got away.
他被绑起来了,这个被切断了,马跑掉了.
Really? Yeah.Did they try chasing him?
真的？是啊.他们有没有追他？
No, no time.It was in a very narrow place.They had no time.
不,没有时间.那是在一个很窄的地方.他们没有时间.
Our star had escaped,
我们的星球逃走了,
but on those narrow mountain passes you can't chase after them.
但是在那些狭窄的山口上你不能追赶他们.
I mean, that would be almost suicidal.
我是说,那几乎是自杀.
So, we had to come up with a new story.
所以,我们必须想出一个新的故事.
The team realised their focus would be less on one horse
团队意识到他们的注意力不会集中在一匹马身上
and more on the connection between gaucho and wild animal.
还有更多关于高乔和野生动物之间的联系.
What Vitito was about to show them was so dangerous
维蒂托要向他们展示的是如此危险
that everyone had to stay out of the corral.
所有人都得远离畜栏.
Vitito's taming style is his own.
维蒂托的驯服风格是他自己的.
His technique captured the attention of the horse
他的技术引起了马的注意
and the crew.
还有船员.
I mean, what we've got going on here with Vitito is
我是说,维蒂托的情况是
he's walking up to this wild horse,
他正走向这匹野马,
he's just managed to captivate her.
他刚刚设法迷住了她.
And you can see in the horse's ears, it's like,
你可以从马的耳朵里看到,
"Do I trust him? Do I not trust him?"
“我信任他吗？我不信任他吗？”
He pulls her in and then pushes her back.
他把她拉进来,然后把她推开.
It's just an incredible connection to be a part of,
这是一种不可思议的联系,
incredible to witness.
难以置信的见证.
In a remarkable three hours,
三个小时后,
the team had the conclusion to their sequence
小组对他们的顺序有了结论
and, along the way, learnt a little of what it takes
一路上,我也学到了一些东西
to be a Patagonian cowboy.
成为巴塔哥尼亚牛仔.
Next time, we travel across Patagonia's dusty plains.
下一次,我们将穿越巴塔哥尼亚尘土飞扬的平原.
To the east, the world becomes drier,
在东方,世界变得更加干燥,
the creatures stranger
陌生人
in their bid to survive these curious badlands.
为了在这些荒野中生存.